

Profile

Industrial Engineer noted for being a professional with strategic thinking, highly adaptable, agile learning, creative and with high level of energy and leadership. 10+ years of demonstrated national and international professional experience in the manufacturing, quality, sales and program management areas. Tier 1,2 & 3 exposure in the automotive industry.

Employment History

Customer Management Specialist, Plexus Corp., Remote location USA

MAY 2023 - PRESENT

Industrial Manufacturing Sector - \$1.5B Global Sales

Responsible of increasing Plexus revenue and profitability by owning the following KPIs with customer: forecasting, contracts, inventory negotiation, project management & RFQs.

Business Dev, Sales & NPI Manager, Interplex, Fort Lauderdale, USA

NOVEMBER 2018 - MAY 2023

Automotive & Medical Manufacturing - \$1B Global Sales

In charge of the business expansion with new or current customers in order to increase profitability of the plant by building, maintaining, and growing customer product portfolios.

Daily responsibilities include: Building costing models, Parts Pricing validation, Capex (capital expenditure), ROI for new investments, RFQ Process owner, CRM Microsoft Dynamics 365, NPI programs, Engineering Changes, Process Change Notifications, New Tooling Implementation, PPAP Process & APQP.

Quality Customer Service Engineer, Adient, Ramos Arizpe, MEX

OCTOBER 2017 - OCTOBER 2018

Automotive - \$14B Global Sales

Quality customer service engineer for project 010B, 370B and 241B (Camry, Avalon and Lexus) 1st Row Driver and Passenger Seat Frames - OEM Toyota.

Advanced Quality Customer Service, Magna Mechanisms, Saltillo, MEX

APRIL 2016 - OCTOBER 2017

Automotive - \$35B Global Sales

Quality Engineer at Assembly Lines for Project RU – Pacifica 2017 Minivan – 2nd and 3rd Row Lines - OEM FCA Chrysler, Magna International Temporal Quality Resident (Liaison) at Windsor, Canada

Industrial Engineer, La-Z-Boy, Mercury & Lennox, Ramos Arizpe, MEX

SEPTEMBER 2012 - APRIL 2016

Early Career Experience; Responsible for leading internal KAIZEN events, focused on increase productivity for operator utilization, space requirements, and production flow improvements. In charge of Identifying opportunities and implement Poke yoke, SMED, KANBAN, and root cause analysis techniques.

Education

Industrial Engineer with Minor in Systems, Instituto Tecnológico y de Estudios Superiores de Monterrey (ITESM), Saltillo, Coahuila, Mexico

AUGUST 2008 - DECEMBER 2013

Details

Fort Lauderdale, FL USA 786-216-9985 joseluis.moncada@hotmail.com

Skills

Leadership
GD&T - Blueprint reading
Building Cost Models
Program/Project Management

Cross Functional in Multiple Departments

Data Analysis

8D Problem Solving

Multicultural Experience (Mexico, USA, Canada)

Bilingual (English & Spanish)
ISO IATF, 9001

Technical Portfolio

Microsoft Office Suite

SAP

Minitab

eDrawings / Autocad

CRM - Microsoft Dynamics 365 Sales

Core Tools

Hobbies

Running Workout Traveling